Summary

Strong C++/Python coding. Experience in driving processor implementation through chip prototype. Deep understanding of computer systems and VLSI. Solid grasp of computer science/machine learning fundamentals. Quick in evaluating/adopting new technologies. Constant learning in software development and efficient ML field.

Experience

Intel Austin, Texas

Computer Architect (System-on-Chip Performance)

2017-present

Analyze, evaluate, project impact of product changes towards server SoC workload performance at power. Applied statistical modeling techniques, regression analysis of workload performance on server platforms. Developed simulator features, multi-simulator integration, metrics parsers, dashboards, visualization, automation. Performed pre-silicon performance tuning, analysis, and validation of interconnect fabric and IO.

Software Engineer (Design Automation)

2016-2017

Developed flows/methodologies for automatic place/route and timing closure of CPU designs (successful tape-in).

Qualcomm Research

San Diego, California

Research Intern Summer 2013

Performed mixed-signal circuit design verification, post-silicon measurements, and FPGA prototyping.

Skills

Programming	Machine Learning/Tools	Processor Implementation
Strong in $\overline{C++}$, Python, Tcl	Strong in Pandas. PyTorch, SKlearn.	SystemVerilog/Verilog, SystemC
Basic Java, Clojure, Javascript, Perl	Git, Docker, Spark, Dashboards, D3	Platform Architect, Simics
Unix shell, HTML, SQL, Node.js	XGBoost, Regressions, Efficient ML	Place-Route, DFT, Timing, DRC/LVS

Select Publications/Awards

A Logic-on-logic 3D-stacked Heterogeneous Multi-core Processor. IEEE ICCD 2017. Physical Design of a 3D-stacked Heterogeneous Multi-core Processor. IEEE 3D-IC 2016. Ranked 34th in USA, IEEExtreme 24-hour Programming Competition, 2014. Team of 2.

Best FPGA Implementation at International LSI Design Contest, Japan 2009. Xilinx Award. Team of 3.

Education

North Carolina State University

RALEIGH, NORTH CAROLINA

Ph.D. in Computer Engineering

3.98/4.0. 2016

Dissertation: Three-Dimensional Integration of Heterogeneous Multi-Core Processors.

Research team built a functional 3D-IC processor chip. Developed custom 3D-IC physical implementation flow. Performed architecture analysis, verification, and entire RTL-GDS2 back-end flow up to deliverable layout.

Teaching Assistant (graduate-level): Design of Digital Systems, Computer Design & Technology.

ASIC Design Software Engineering Advanced Microarchitecture Electronic Sys. Level Design Computer Networks Parallel Computer Arch. ASIC Verification Physical Design IC Technology & Fabrication Memory Systems Computer Design & Tech. VLSI Systems Design Embedded Systems Design Digital Electronics Modern Comp. Algebra-AU VLSI System Testing (Duke U.)

Duke University

Durham, North Carolina

Visiting Scholar: coursework, research collaboration

2013

Bandung Institute of Technology

Indonesia

B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Computer Engineering track), with distinction

JAPAN

Thesis: C implementation neural network and Kohonen SOM, training/inference, floating/fixed point, on a multi-core Parallax microcontroller. TA: Digital Systems, Microprocessor Lab.

Oita University

Exchange Student, Research & Coursework

2007-2008

Research: Implemented face follower on a panning camera using neural networks (implemented in C).

Project Experience

Machine Learning

PyTorch: Integrated and analyzed model quantization coupled with feedback alignment training algorithm (open-source libraries).

Experimented on developing custom learning algorithms (back-propagation algorithm alternatives), e.g binarized neural network with greedy training approach.

Benchmarking of MobileNet, SqueezeNet quantized/non-quantized models on Android using TensorFlow Lite.

Silicon Implementation / Tape-outs

Successful academic tape-out (functional 3D-IC processor chip) of a heterogeneous multi-core processor system with thread migration features at NCSU. Processor implementation has two stacked dies of $5.25 \text{ mm} \times 5.25 \text{ mm}$ on a 130 nm process.

RTL Design, FPGA Prototyping

Implemented "Sokoban" (moving box puzzle game) on FPGA: coded the game in MIPS assembly by hand (prototyped in C). Wrote MIPS processor RTL from scratch (team effort, 1 GHz clock in a commercial 180 nm process). Wrote the Verilog code to interface with FPGA buttons and render VGA graphics. Created game sprites.

Memory Systems

Performed modelling and performance comparison between ideal and non-ideal block placement policy for multi-core systems. Cache block placement policy: requestor core cache vs remote core cache. Analyzed experiment results from running SPEC2K benchmarks in SIMICS.

ESL & Physical Design

Performed TLM & ESL modelling of an SoC design that consists of an ARM Cortex core, DRAM model, and AMBA bus. Performed physical design optimizations, signal integrity analysis, power analysis, timing analysis. Tools: SystemC, Mentor Graphics Vista, Catapult, Python, C++, UML, Encounter, Primetime.

Parallel Computer Architecture

Implemented a MSI, MESI, MOESI cache coherence protocols simulator in C++.

Explored cache coherence protocols to reduce off-chip memory accesses.

Computer Design and Technology

Implemented a generic cache simulator, branch target buffer simulator, and Tomasulo superscalar processsor simulator in C++.

Implemented a checkpoint recovery mechanism for large fetch window processor within SimpleScalar simulator environment in C++.

Advanced Microarchitecture

Implemented and compared thread migration strategies within SimpleScalar simulator in C++.

ASIC Verification

Verified an out-of-order superscalar core (FabScalar) for tape-out, found design bugs in load-store unit and issue queue. Created a reusable SystemVerilog testbench executed in QuestaSim.

Digital Electronics

Designed a low power Hybrid Latch Flip-flop in academic 45 nm tech library. Operating clock frequency 4GHz, power consumption 19.9 uW, setup time 13.5ps, hold time 86ps, t_{DQ} of 63.64 ps.

Designed a voltage-mode and current-mode differential transmitter circuit. Tools: HSPICE.

VLSI Systems Design

Designed a full-custom 3x3 arbiter-crossbar CMOS unit, 2nd best performance and energy*delay-squared metric out of 27 teams. Customized power delivery network and clock tree design. Created custom standard cell library and top-level integration. Achieved 5.5 GHz clock frequency, 0.19 nW power, with FreePDK45 technology library. Tools: Cadence Virtuoso, HSPICE, Calibre DRC-LFD.

ASIC Design

Implemented a Viterbi Decoder in RTL Verilog. Optimized throughput and delay per unit area metric by designing a fast floating point unit, using dual port memory, and pipelining.

Online Courses

Machine Learning, Startup Engineering, Analysis of Algorithms (Coursera) – Scalable Machine Learning (edX).